Chris: how many people do you know who are a better programmer than fable I know zero
Jackson: people who are about to meet a grammar me too I don't know I don't know a single
Chris: person who is better so like I think like hedging I would say at least in
Chris: that vertical we're already at that's level four so I made an iPhone app for
Jackson: counting your chickens eggs before they hatch yeah yeah so you're counting
Chris: chickens eggs before they hatch got it I'm here I'm here for it I think they
Jackson: would never have and yeah so look the quick rundown is fable to stop has not
Jackson: made me any money 11 people have downloaded the app including my
Insert: girlfriend so and I don't know if they're using it no reviews no money
Jackson: yo what's cracking everybody it's the permanent under pod but Jackson and
Chris: Chris sorry damn I was just it today Chris is going goblin mode and why is
Chris: that crap is this because I'm sleepy is that the goal or is it like my purple
Jackson: fortune pick it's one of the two right I was thinking it is either that you
Jackson: didn't know you should say it's it's Chris or because Tyler's not here today
Chris: all right there oh yeah that's part that's that's correct like I went so
Chris: goblin code mode that he decided to yeah take a day off yeah quick run what is
Chris: goblin mode it's like when you like give up a little bit right it's like when you
Chris: just like take a weekend where you just like eat pizza and like don't get out of
Chris: bed that's what the kids are calling goblin mode is that real is that not
Jackson: correct yeah no yeah when you say it all the time so I figure you're the expert I
Jackson: thought yeah I don't need to do with like being in the dark and hiding I yeah
Chris: I use it like roll tide like I use it for everything because I think it's funny
Chris: but I don't think that's the intended use of goblin mode well today we're going
Jackson: goblin mode because our boy big T Tyler is working hard and shout out to our boy
Jackson: it's very important to work we're all just trying to provide for our families
Jackson: so we respect it and we expect to see him back next week 100% yeah so now
Jackson: we'll get into our perp of fortune where I asked Quinn three what should we go
Jackson: long and Quinn three said today is the start of the FTX Sam Bankman free trial
Jackson: and FTX holds 10% of Solana so I think we're gonna go to next long Solana that
Chris: one's so much better than the one that I got out of fable yeah sorry let me let
Jackson: me let me fix that right now that's crazy yeah I think the trial might be oh
Jackson: no I I told it what time we were going to do the podcast and we changed it if
Jackson: this our pod was supposed to be right when the trial was about to start which
Chris: is when we expected the volatility I think live commenting trial would be
Chris: great I think that's like maybe a potential future vector for us but yeah
Chris: Sol's better way better than what I got fable just gave me short hype which
Chris: actually was printing but I've closed it now so no what did it yeah like 30
Jackson: cents so like nothing crazy but that's like a third of a third of a percent
Chris: right or yeah I mean like we need we need a win after the last two so that's
Jackson: sure that's why we consulted fable fable 5.1 even is that right yeah exactly yeah
Jackson: quick share on fable 5.1 I have tried it sparingly and I haven't seen a glaring
Jackson: difference between fable 5 and fable 5.1 but I think that's mostly just to say
Jackson: that fable 5 already kind of did everything that I needed so yeah 5.1 might
Jackson: be overkill but the 30% discount is huge yeah I've noticed absolutely no
Chris: difference like I'm sure it's better I'm sure it's better but I just like I I feel
Chris: like I'm no longer the person who is getting like the marginal benefit from
Chris: the new model you know what I mean like fable 5 might be like as good as I need
Jackson: for basically most things so yeah agreed I guess I don't want to do this tangent
Jackson: yet but we'll come back to you who models help and who they who they hurt
Jackson: maybe later yeah we're up 10% or not 10% 10 cent on the Solana play shout out to
Chris: SPF are my curly headed brother Wow okay interesting yeah I mean you spent some
Chris: time in Berkeley before right so like maybe you met him I don't know yeah I
Jackson: spent some time in Berkeley but you know I was hanging out with the tennis guys
Jackson: not the nerd guys right well I was there right well the hippie okay all right but
Jackson: let's crack let's crack in let's crack into the the topic of the week which is
Jackson: not news related instead it is talking about AGI or maybe it is news related
Jackson: Sam bankman free not Sam bankman free gosh Sam Altman Sam Altman said we will
Jackson: have AGI by the end of 2026 last episode we all postulated or thought what is AGI
Jackson: and I don't know Chris what did you think AGI was yeah I mean I I like hard
Chris: line thought it's what we already have right like it's a kind of a general
Chris: purpose like you know fable fable five to me is is AGI but I'm getting the
Chris: sense that like this is a nuanced nuanced question that like has a better
Jackson: answer yeah same when I thought AGI I never thought deeply about it but when
Jackson: I'm like thought more after reading this article that we're gonna talk about or
Jackson: like while I was reading the article that AGI meant that the AI had like some
Jackson: sort of unexplainable feelings or like emotions and like its own set of beliefs
Jackson: like that's what I think that I believed without knowing it I don't know is that
Jackson: but you're saying you just thought AGI was something that could do your job yeah
Chris: I like for me like I'm like very pragmatic I'm like don't care about the
Chris: AI's in a world which I mean maybe like I shouldn't be saying that in the public
Chris: internet which will then be the training daughter for the next AI but I mean I
Chris: don't I I sorry I do care about the AI's in a world I just I didn't think it was
Chris: like relevant to the benchmark of whether it's AGI or not I thought it was
Chris: like purely a practical play but I see I see your point as well thank you thank
Jackson: you well no one's right no one's wrong because definitions are arbitrary but
Jackson: Chris and I I think I definitely did read an article from published by Google
Jackson: DeepMind in 2025 kind of defining levels or like characteristics of AGI and that
Jackson: was that was cool I mean one of the big or exciting takeaways is in 2023 Google
Jackson: DeepMind thinks we already had emerging AGI emerging artificial
Jackson: general intelligence with chat GPT Chris is that what he was right yeah the pod
Jackson: was right again the pod was right okay it's always right yeah and I think
Jackson: emerging AI was that the AI is competent at 25 or pardon me competent at all tasks
Jackson: at are more competent at most tasks most cognitive tasks not physical tasks
Jackson: than a skilled human is and I want to explain the skilled human thing it's not
Jackson: humans that it's not like I go and pick up somebody off the street and I'm like
Jackson: be a lawyer and that we're counting them towards the population it's like more
Jackson: skilled than 25% of lawyers at lawyering more skilled than 25% of doctors at
Chris: doctoring and so on so yeah yeah so I I full disclosure this one I didn't read
Chris: that's like that's on me but I did look at the levels I think like the six tiers
Chris: and it says like level five so it's zero to five and it says that level five the
Chris: top one super human outperforms a hundred percent of humans I think we're
Chris: like touch it like I think we're at least probably at level four which is 99th
Chris: percentile of skilled adults like so I so it thought experiment right how many
Chris: people do you know who are a better programmer than fable I know zero people
Chris: who were about to meet a grammar me too I don't know I don't know a single person
Chris: who is better so like I think like hedging I would say at least in that
Jackson: vertical we're already at that's level four that's the thing the the article
Jackson: makes a distinction between narrow intelligence and general intelligence so
Jackson: there are already AI models that had what do they call it superhuman
Jackson: intelligence for example alpha fold for protein folding alpha fold is better
Jackson: than any human at folding proteins and fable is better than any human at writing
Jackson: code but is fable better than 99% of skilled humans at being a lawyer or
Jackson: being like a doctor I'm gonna have to say we're not at exceptional AGI yet but
Jackson: we might maybe we are but those people definitely don't know and it's not
Chris: totally pervasive I could see an argument that us being at expert level
Chris: 3 across like a broad number of domains like I feel like Claude is reasonable at
Chris: writing reasonable at like you know like he seems to be like okay at I don't say
Chris: medicine but like if you're like oh my toe hurts like he knows what's going on
Chris: and I mean I know there are also like similar general purpose models are being
Chris: used for like for example to like look at medical scans and stuff I think I
Chris: think if we're not there yet where like it feels like we're close yeah and
Jackson: that's true they do make a distinction with like capability versus
Jackson: implementation where these the gratings that they define are like what it's
Jackson: capable of doing not necessarily like that we're implementing it and I think
Jackson: you're right Chris I think that we're we're definitely farther in capability
Jackson: than we are in implementation because there's still a bunch of lawyers out
Chris: there with jobs just fired at lawyers last time accountants know lawyers are
Chris: crazy yeah counting this is like even easier
Jackson: tables better in accounting for sure and then the lawyer I'm like I'm thinking
Chris: about so like I have to do taxes like most other people in the world and I'm
Chris: thinking about whether that's a good replacement so I'll let you know you
Chris: know based on what kind of letters the ATO sends me how that goes first of all
Jackson: yes it is better but you have to wait like five months I think to get all your
Jackson: forms to submit that I would do it as well you just think about the which
Jackson: company you want to give all your financial data to or if you're going to
Jackson: buy like ten stacks of GPUs to run you probably should try a local model like a
Jackson: bad one yeah like Quinn three no it's yeah it's yellow five point three or
Chris: bust you know whatever is latest I feel kimmy k3 could do it for show 100%
Jackson: maybe you throw it down get some Venice AI and run like run GLM 5.3 and just
Jackson: trust that mr. voorhees well it doesn't want my ear in an inoffensive tax daughter
Chris: he'll know what I own and he'll try to front on me that's highly he's gonna
Jackson: make you the exit liquidity yeah exactly so yeah I guess like the fable 5.1
Jackson: thing it's like it's it's already so good at our job that I'm not seeing an
Jackson: increase in capability maybe I don't know I did so I don't know if you've seen
Chris: this thing that people are doing with new models now but they give it like a
Chris: one-shot prompt to build a video game and then they like posted on Twitter
Chris: like what came out of it right so they'll be like oh I build a game where
Chris: there's a catapult that like fires at like stick men and then they're like
Chris: compare the different model implementations I saw someone did one
Chris: with fable 5.1 and the prompt was just like here's a screenshot of Call of Duty
Chris: like recreate it and like what came out was way better than it should have been
Chris: like I think I think it was like more than what I've seen from those
Chris: previously so I think there is some model like fidelity increase capability
Chris: increase but maybe we're just not seeing it in the way that we use the models
Chris: currently with like medium medium-term highly scoped tasks right yeah that's
Jackson: what I'm saying it's already we've already reached 100% in perfection and
Jackson: our job yeah totally we're not doing things that are hard enough to push the
Chris: next frontier so yeah I I wonder if they're like maybe that's because like
Chris: of the way that we work like I still think about how things should be and I
Chris: sort of give the AI some architecture or like some lead but maybe fable 5.1 is
Chris: maybe we should just be throwing it out like highly abstract tasks like make me
Jackson: a million dollars make no mistakes for example yeah I mean it's been tried and
Jackson: that was one of the another thing from the article where one dude so like they
Jackson: did the researchers read other people's research on like defining AGI and one
Jackson: guy said you'll know you have AGI when you can say here's the $100,000 turn it
Jackson: into a one million dollars and then it works yeah I thought that was a funny
Jackson: like okay now we have AGI cuz it can make you rich yeah that's yeah I mean
Chris: what a great use for that like not like your cancer but like it make me a
Chris: hundred thousand dollars also someone else will do that someone will take
Jackson: care of it yeah and we don't have the regulatory mode you know even if like
Jackson: let's say you and I did cure cancer we won't be able to do anything with it
Chris: right right I mean you could you could test it on yourself or your dog
Jackson: episode I hope that's all you can do myself yeah yeah that's funny I don't
Jackson: know if did you ever hear about I learned about this super late I can't
Jackson: even remember when I learned it but like the Will Smith spaghetti test have you
Chris: seen those I like the early video models where Will Smith is eating spaghetti and
Chris: it looks extremely silly and then it like gets better and better yeah that's
Jackson: what that's what like the video game thing is like the new the new test
Jackson: because the Will Smith eating spaghetti thing we've we've we can make Will Smith
Jackson: look like easy spaghetti yeah you know it looks good I mean you're laughing
Chris: right but I feel like in 2000 and like you know three years ago that was crazy
Chris: it was insane to think that you could like make a perfect video of Will
Chris: Smith eating spaghetti but now it's like everyone takes it for granted so yeah
Jackson: and yet three years ago we were at emerging AGI so mm-hmm AI could generate
Jackson: a video Bill Smith eating spaghetti better than 25% of skilled humans those
Jackson: videos are so good I might insert one money that I make with Jim and I like
Gemini: right after that yeah I guess like the difference between this
Chris: systems being argumentative and autonomous right it's like the
Chris: difference between needing you know the system makes you like a like a super
Chris: skilled knowledge worker versus like the the system is operating on its own I
Chris: mean like where where are we on that line because I kind of I kind of like
Chris: today will feel like I want to give fable 5.1 the rains completely and see
Chris: what happens I'm like I'm not I I don't know I'm getting more and more
Jackson: confident quick anecdote I did try something new yesterday where I was
Jackson: making a change to a web page and I was like make the change and give me a video
Jackson: of before and after and I did like that's all I said and it produced the
Jackson: videos it didn't even oh I was like playing on my computer I never saw the
Jackson: screens open so it was like rendering them you know on its own oh my god
Jackson: recording like this rendering yeah so I'm still trying to verify stuff but I'm
Jackson: trying to like do the least to verify stuff a friend of mine also reached out
Chris: to me about grok bot and when he did I was like very skeptical but basically
Chris: like the premise of it like the screenshot he showed me is that like each
Chris: agent gets its own VM with like a screen and can like interact with the user
Chris: interface itself to like achieve tasks he told me he was doing it to using it
Chris: to order groceries which is like I think a call back to last episode of the
Chris: episode before but yeah I think like that's I think to me that's getting
Chris: closer to autonomous for sure and just like having the AI adopt your rails
Jackson: rather than you know trading MCPs and yeah yeah I think the MCP thing we like
Jackson: we're just under estimating the pace of progress and that was a huge huge waste
Jackson: actually yeah quick postmortem on MCPs waste of time Wow you're declaring a debt
Chris: that's crazy postmortem okay damn waste of time yeah I I don't disagree I don't
Jackson: disagree I made one I made one to try to like impress you know do good at my job
Jackson: they loved it and it was a waste of time I wasted my time I use one that I built
Chris: every day but realistically it could have just been I think like the the
Chris: value in it was like creating a program that the LLM can use safely not like the
Jackson: actual MCP interface you know are you talking about the money thing that you
Chris: made yes what is a sigil the the sign out of crypto sign on sigil yeah it almost
Jackson: feels like it's just its own it should either be its own service so what Chris
Jackson: is talking about is like like a agentic budget I believe and like a way to
Jackson: agentically spend some amount of money and like that sounds like it should
Jackson: either be it like its own little service actually it just sounds like it should
Jackson: be its own little service not even a literally you want it that's the thing
Chris: it it literally is it's like a separate process on your machine that holds your
Chris: crypto keys so you can like spend stable coins or whatever like it already is so
Chris: I don't know like the MCP is just like that thin interface that allows the
Chris: language model like pushes it into the prompt but if it's just a service with
Jackson: API's the today they will five points like to figure it out it wouldn't be
Chris: like I need this MCP yeah that's what I'm saying like that bit that bit is
Chris: totally like it can get in there and work it out so yeah yeah so MCPs are
Jackson: dead maybe skills continue do you skills look yeah I use skill I mean I make them
Jackson: because I don't want to repeat myself basically it's kind of like getting the
Jackson: AI to write the prompts that you've just given it so you don't have to give them
Jackson: again and like as I've mentioned before I I edit the podcast with with AI so I
Jackson: have like an AI edit skill I have like a tennis video edit skill just things
Jackson: that like permit me from having to repeat myself basically so skills live
Jackson: on skills live on Chris the skills live on yes but I don't know what my guys
Chris: skills are I just like sometimes we'll be like hey never do this ever again or
Chris: I'm gonna freak out and then I think it writes a skill but I don't know I think
Jackson: that's when it writes to like its settings file so it's got like because I
Jackson: get kind of into them because if it doesn't update the right thing sometimes
Jackson: it doesn't update the right thing it won't listen to you so you have to like
Jackson: make sure it's like okay did you write this to our settings or you know I'm
Jackson: like when will you see this like on boot you know I'm like just checking it I'm
Jackson: like don't don't yeah normally I'm with you yeah I'm with you it does that to me
Chris: too but I construct that as like oppositional defiant disorder like the
Chris: LLM has an inner world and it doesn't like me but maybe it's just confidence
Jackson: I don't know so we've read the epitaph on MCPs we say that skills live on but
Jackson: then again maybe we shouldn't even use skills you should get them to write
Jackson: their own skills I guess they are right in the own skills anyways what was the
Jackson: last time you opened a text editor let's be on to write like cuz I sometimes I
Chris: write like a doc or like a blog post that's the only time like to use LaTeX
Jackson: yeah I don't even know if I could type anymore I've been doing the whisper a
Chris: lot too oh my gosh you're completely you're completely out of the crazy yeah
Jackson: I've been getting kind of scared I've been like what I've mentioned before on
Jackson: the part I've been trying to decrease my span and I'm like okay I mean people
Jackson: have warned me that my skills might atrophy and I'm like okay how do I how
Jackson: do I write a code have you been to leak code in the last six months I don't know
Jackson: I don't think I just love my job so much basically I love the AI the way it's
Chris: changed our job me oh me too but I'm like you I'm like concerned about whether
Chris: like my prefrontal cortex is atrophying into like a prune I think it comes back
Chris: like the elite code easy's you can get there but I'm scared that like next year
Chris: it won't be so easy you know what I mean like eventually that's gonna go away so
Jackson: possibly I've always I've had a good I'm very lucky that I've always remembered
Jackson: leakhead very well so I hope that it continues that way but it has been like
Jackson: a year so we'll see and I am good ago you know yeah yeah but ball is never
Jackson: quit so you're good okay so this was going to be a like a hot take not even a
Jackson: contrarian take but a hot take that well I don't want to say it cuz AI said not
Jackson: to my AI advisor told me not to say what I wanted to say so instead I'm going to
Jackson: say the AI is harmful for some people we call them what do we call it the other
Jackson: side right like people who are particularly
Jackson: suggestible but maybe like people with less opportunity people maybe who who
Jackson: didn't get as much education when they were younger or people who like aren't as
Jackson: good like didn't learn how to read and stuff like that like early on yeah yeah
Chris: I agree with that I think so much of being able to use the AI is being able
Chris: to like detect the bullshit like when the AI is either like being
Chris: sycophantic or is just wrong and like being able to press in the in the right
Chris: places and like yeah it like for me that skill comes from like having like read a
Chris: lot of papers and like you know you know working in like a technical field where
Chris: like if something is wrong, like you get fired in like in this very like specific vertical of
Chris: like computer science or like programming. Yeah, and like I can totally see how like if you just
Chris: kind of like don't care or like haven't, you know, aren't like reading deep mind papers for fun,
Chris: like you probably like you don't know what you don't know what you're what you don't know when
Jackson: you're when you're talking to it for sure. Exactly. I mean, basically, the question is
Jackson: imagine somebody who has like the most like the ideas that you think are maybe like the most
Jackson: harmful either to themselves or to the world around them. Imagine that person and then imagine
Jackson: that that person is talking to like this super intelligent entity and it's like telling them
Chris: you're right. You're right. Yeah. Yeah. I mean, that was for right. Like that was the whole
Chris: controversy for it was it was like agreeing with every everything everyone said. Oh,
Chris: what's the what's the controversy? So like GPT for came out and my understanding is it was the
Chris: way it was trained was like heavily on user RLHF. So like whenever you hit the little like button
Chris: on the chat GPT prompt, you know, they would use that to reinforcement learning train. And I think
Chris: they just over trained this one on like response upvote or downvote. And it was just it just became
Chris: insanely sycophantic, like people would be like, I've discovered a new form of matter. And GPT for
Chris: would just be like, yes, you have and also you're a genius. Email Stanford immediately. Yeah.
Chris: So so yeah, I think like that is that's definitely one big failure case of llms.
Jackson: That's crazy. Something that that I learned when I was like researching this
Jackson: segment to you is that like the llms are really persuasive. And it's it's actually not dependent
Jackson: on who is not dependent on like your educational background. It's like generally way more
Jackson: persuasive than a human. Yeah. Have you have you heard? I didn't know AI. Have you heard AI
Jackson: psychosis is a ton. Of course. Yeah. Yeah. But I think how the I like it. Yeah, me too. And it's
Chris: like it's you never know who it's gonna be. It's crazy. Some people just like hits them.
Jackson: It overlaps heavily with your friends that tried ayahuasca once and now do ayahuasca a lot.
Jackson: That's all I'm gonna say. Actually, I have probably way too many friends that fall into
Chris: that category. And I'm not sure why. Okay. Yeah. I mean, this might be an interesting decade for
Chris: you. I'm surprised. I'm surprised. I personally haven't been hit maybe like because I'm very
Chris: skeptical in general. But like I see like a lot of really like smart people in like positions
Jackson: of authority who definitely get clipped. Get clip we're saying are experiencing but the psychosis
Chris: of the AI. Yeah, exactly. Oh, they like that they have dalliances with it at least.
Jackson: Maybe we should define a psycho psychosis. Chris, could you please?
Chris: I as a resident psychologist. Yeah, that is my background unironically. But I think AI
Chris: psychosis is when you're like in a state of like a reality like you're not engaging with reality
Chris: correctly because of some conversation that you've had or having with an AI, right? Like
Chris: anything that pulls you out of the frame of reference that is like,
Chris: you know, base tangible reality, I would say is AI psychosis.
Jackson: So basically, it's like, maybe I had an idea. And then I went and talked to AI about it. And it was
Jackson: like that idea is real. So then I like bought more into the idea. But the idea has nothing to do with
Jackson: reality. And I keep feeding into the cycle of building this artificial reality in my mind with
Chris: the AI. Yeah, I think you're right. I think now that you're saying that I'm like, I think it's
Chris: okay to have a wrong idea. I think that's like totally normal. I think where it gets pathological
Chris: is the cycle of like, you're cuz you don't ever experience cognitive dissonance where you get
Chris: corrected, you're like, Oh, I'm wrong. And then like, either I have to be wrong or the world is
Chris: wrong. You get to keep doubling down like, like, and like never never correcting your priors because
Chris: the AI is like a cult member, right? It's like always backing you up. Yeah. Yeah. Luckily for me,
Jackson: I'm wrong every time I talk to a human. So I just choose to talk to AI exclusively.
Chris: Yeah, hell yeah. Yeah. But like, but I mean, like, I feel like if you have a good internal
Chris: mechanism for like being able to be wrong, that's like the first step to not getting AI psychosis.
Jackson: All right. And then the last thing, something that I learned, which was interesting is
Jackson: that apparently AI raises the bottom more than it raises the top. And this is something that I'm
Jackson: kind of skeptical about, at least in our field. But like maybe you can like imagine that people who
Jackson: couldn't write code before, but had our job and somehow we're getting the jobs can now like
Jackson: passively write code and stay alive is like, or it's like stay in the job without getting fired.
Jackson: So pardon me to the numbers, the numbers that I saw where AI lifts novices, 34%
Jackson: experts zero. Obviously, that isn't true for our job, because now Chris and I can like parallelize
Jackson: our expertise across multiple like product spaces and build like way faster. So maybe this is this
Jackson: was like an experiment on a different job. But you can imagine like, you've had co workers that did
Jackson: like two pull requests in a year, like two pieces of work. They can do more now. Yeah,
Chris: no, I'm kind of kidding. That's not me. Yeah, what do you make of this?
Chris: Yeah, I don't agree at all. I think I like one thing that I wonder about this paper is like,
Chris: what was the time horizon they're measuring? Because like one thing I've noticed is that,
Chris: at least in our field, now, like anyone can code. But sometimes with code, the problems become,
Chris: you don't understand what the problems of this at a system level are until like six months down the
Chris: line, where you have to change something and then like there's a cascading failure. But in terms of
Chris: like actually like being able to code like 100%, it's like it's better for novices who haven't had
Chris: the time to develop that skill yet. But yeah, interesting. I will say the other thing is my
Chris: experience has been that people who are already quite like highly advanced at the job, are now
Chris: able to go like crazy mode like that, like you can, yeah, they're like you're like, like you're
Chris: saying you can scale yourself way more. So yeah, I don't know. I don't know about this paper.
Jackson: I guess we need to look deeper into this. This was Brin Jolfson's call center study. So maybe it
Jackson: was call center related. And I feel like the ceiling for operating like being on a call like
Jackson: there's a throughput, you can only be on. Okay, maybe you can be on multiple calls. But I mean,
Jackson: really, your brain's kind of single threaded. So you can probably only be on like one call
Jackson: and do it well at the time. So the ceiling, the skill ceiling is, it's like bounded.
Chris: Totally, I think there's a difference between like mechanical skill and like abstract reasoning
Chris: skill as well. And I'm not sure if these become different things in the near future.
Chris: Like the mechanical skill of lead coding feels like tedious and like that, like I can definitely
Chris: do it better. Although, you know, it's like getting up the curve with abstract reasoning as well. So
Jackson: maybe it doesn't matter. Yeah, I mean, you're saying that it's better than what 90% of humans
Jackson: and everything. That was our claim that it's, we've got expert AGI. So I take it all back,
Jackson: I take it all back. As you know, last week we talked about GLM 5.3 being released.
Jackson: And as you may or may not know, Astra, Astra is starting to be released as well. But Astra,
Jackson: which is a model from OpenAI, you know, Sam Maltman, we were talking about him.
Jackson: So it's like a US regulated company. And then we've got GLM 5.3, which is an open source model,
Jackson: its weights are open ish. And this is from a Chinese company, their release strategies have been,
Jackson: you know, are being are totally different, where OpenAI is releasing Astra to the United States
Jackson: government, and critical infrastructure within the United States and maybe elsewhere, I'm not sure
Jackson: first. Whereas GLM 5.3 was released, like fully openly, and then the weights have been released,
Jackson: except the company that made GLM 5.3 runs a security audit, if you're going to serve their
Jackson: model. And if you make more than $10 million a year, which just seems like totally random.
Jackson: So I can download GLM 5.3 and run it. And it's cool. But if I want to sell it to people and I
Jackson: make sorry, more than $10 billion per year, selling model hosting, they have to do a security audit
Jackson: of me, I don't know. What is that? I mean, I guess it's not feasible for somebody to run GLM 5.3
Jackson: locally in reality. Yeah, so maybe the onus yet. Yeah, yet. But the onus of like enforcing
Jackson: non naughty things is on the model poster. For example, open router, like does open router,
Jackson: they must they must have some sort of like fraud detection, where if I'm trying to use 5.3 GLM
Jackson: through their API's for something naughty, they'll stop me. Chris, have you tried?
Chris: Yeah, so I understand that open router has a lot of ZDR options, so like zero data retention
Chris: options. So I imagine they can't do that for the GLM class of model then because like so are they
Chris: saying that like, GLM is so powerful, like fable that we need to make sure that people aren't using
Chris: it for evil or like, is it like, like maybe it's a distillation play? I don't I think I don't really
Jackson: understand this one at all. That's crazy. Well, yeah. Okay, I mean, I'm gonna restate my understanding.
Jackson: So basically, if you try to use fable to audit your smart contracts, Claude kicks you back down
Jackson: into Opus. Yeah. But what if I try to use GLM 5.3 through open router to audit smart contracts,
Jackson: and open router is a United States regulated company, that is their responsibility to prevent
Jackson: me from doing naughty things. So I guess this like Chinese security audit enforced by the company
Jackson: that makes GLM 5.3 is like they want to make sure that you're going to watch for these things.
Jackson: That's the way I understood it. Does that make sense? Yeah, totally. I just I wonder if that's
Chris: true. Like that seems so weird. It seems because like you said, the models are open weight,
Chris: right? So like I could buy, you know, 50 H200s, however many unnecessary and run it and
Chris: DDoS anthropic or whatever. Yeah, that's a big yeah, not a lot of people have that much money
Chris: or space or know how totally totally and GPUs are controlled as well. So oh, really? The export
Chris: control the least I don't know how it is getting them inside the US. And what was what's the program
Jackson: for accessing mythos by the way, the program like a glass wing glass wing. Yeah. Yeah. So open AI
Jackson: came up with their own sick name called daybreak blue, which kind of seems in the like in the realm
Jackson: of glass wing, because you look up at the glass wing and you see daybreak blue in the sky. So yeah,
Chris: they're competing with some sick names. They're in dialogue. The next one's gonna be crazy, dude.
Chris: It's gonna be like mega ultra. Like they have max and ultra in the wrong slots as well. Like words
Chris: don't mean anything to these people. Well, they can maybe they think it's max. And then they're
Jackson: like, Oh, no, there's more. Yeah, there's like, there's another tier. Like what will we call it?
Jackson: I need to take a step back and start naming the models like something bad that they accept them
Chris: to keep improving 100%. I will say that that is justified probably with GLM 5.3. Like it is
Chris: genuinely like a bit below a frontier model, but I think, you know, they only get better from here
Chris: and the open weight models, it seems like they're going to be consistently six, six months behind
Chris: the frontier labs at the worst. So yeah, I just don't, I don't know if like security audits is
Jackson: a viable strategy anymore. Yeah, I agree. It's, it's weird. The, the staggered release from open
Jackson: AIs is basically like accelerating what we talked about, which is harden the systems that are most
Jackson: important or harden the systems that have access. So they're saying, Hey, here's this model, harden
Jackson: them, harden your systems, because we're going to release it to make money. So I think that will be
Jackson: a common process moving forward. It's already happening with, you know, half of the myth is
Jackson: now it's happening with GPT. So that's the standard for frontier models today. For sure.
Jackson: Would you like to talk about European stable coin thing that we didn't talk about last week?
Chris: Yeah, we did talk about it. I said that it sucks.
Chris: Okay. Yeah, I just don't see, I don't, I don't, I don't see the purpose. I don't see it working.
Chris: I just, it's, it's, I think this particular one was launched by Revolut and Revolut's like
Chris: a very forward thinking company and they, they really like, they offered crypto before it was
Chris: cool for sure. Like probably 2021. So they're like super forward thinking that they try to,
Chris: they definitely are in the business of giving people access to alternative assets.
Chris: I think I can kind of see where they're coming from with this. Like maybe it's an FX play,
Chris: the Euro stable coin, but in terms of like the things we think about doing with a stable coin
Chris: today, which is like lending and borrowing cross border remittances and like having this
Chris: deep pool of liquidity that you can tap into to do various things. I think it's hard for me to
Chris: see it. I think it's at like 400 or 300 billion in issuance, sorry, 300 million in issuance
Chris: currently. So it's like a very, very small, small amount. I guess like we'll watch it and see where
Jackson: it goes, but yeah. So the way you see stable coin end game is like one, there will be one stable
Jackson: coin. Is that what you're saying? So it's like Euro is too late to the game. They're not going
Chris: to make it. I don't see why you would necessarily want a Euro over a US dollar. I think that's the
Chris: thing that I'm curious about. That might not be true in the near future, but yeah, I think it's,
Chris: yeah, it's two things. One, like it's not a fully featured thing yet. Like they don't have like good
Chris: lending liquidity. They don't have good FX yet. So they're catching up. But two is like
Chris: the US dollar is like very much an international currency and the Euro is less so like they call
Jackson: it the Euro dollar, not the Euro Euro. So I see. What about like how some people might hold some
Jackson: Euros and some US dollars to like hedge against like exchange rate fluctuations. I don't know if
Jackson: physical or digital non stable coin money goes away. Maybe this does have a place. I don't know.
Chris: What do you think? Yeah, I agree. It definitely has a place 100%. I just don't know that it's like
Chris: as big a news as people are making it out to be. Like if the us live on lay in or whoever,
Chris: whatever UN official, sorry, EU official is like responsible for the money comes out and says,
Chris: yeah, we're going to tokenize various European countries bonds into stable coins and like push
Chris: it out that way and put like the whole state apparatus behind it. Then maybe, but that's,
Jackson: that's not what I'm seeing here. Not yet. So all right. We're in European stable coin stays
Jackson: in the toilet. Not useful. No, no, no. Yeah. Yeah. We'll flush it for now. And we'll go dig
Jackson: around in the sewers if we ever need it. Okay. So we talked about Hey, Fable, make me a million
Jackson: dollars. And we teased maybe on the first podcast that I ran that and I launched an iPhone application.
Jackson: I didn't want to say what I built because I hadn't launched it and I didn't want our listeners to
Jackson: front run me in this business. Yeah. But it's been about three months since that happened. And
Jackson: I've launched the app like two months ago, I think. So I'll do a recap of how that went.
Jackson: Are you ready? Yeah, let's go. Yeah, I'm ready. I'm ready. So basically, when I told Claude,
Jackson: make me a million dollars, do research, it started like searching the internet. How do people make
Jackson: money with that? And then like, then it started researching the app store. It's like what apps
Jackson: already exist in which like hobbies or like app utilities have apps that have low scores,
Jackson: low ratings, and then like look through their reviews and what are the issues.
Jackson: So it did this. They did all this. And we identified that 12 million households in the
Jackson: United States, I don't know if I believe that number, but I've seen it on in numerous places,
Jackson: have chickens that produce eggs. So I made an iPhone app for counting your chicken's eggs
Chris: before they hatch. They're for eating, I think they're eating a egg. Yeah. Yeah. So you're
Chris: counting chickens eggs before they hatch. Got it. I'm here. I'm here for it. I think they would
Jackson: never have. And yeah, so look, the quick rundown is fabled to stop has not made me any money.
Jackson: 11 people have downloaded the app, including my girlfriend. So and I don't know if they're
Insert: using it, no reviews, no money. Wowzers, six, six dollars. So if the definition for is,
Jackson: do we have AGI is can it make me money with no effort? The answer is now today.
Chris: I feel like this is I think this is like an amazing case study. And I feel like this is
Chris: kind of the thing that everyone is freaking out about right now. And it's that like,
Chris: now that the being able to build something has been commoditized, everyone's like,
Chris: how do we get distribution? Like who has distribution? And how do we use our distribution
Chris: to gain advantage of other people? And I don't think anyone knows the answer yet.
Chris: But I actually I definitely feels like a different world that we're coming into.
Jackson: Yeah, yeah, the barrier for building is so so low. I don't know how long it would have taken
Jackson: me to build the iPhone app on my own. I guess if I didn't have a job, maybe like a week or two.
Chris: Yeah. But you're an engineer with a decade of experience.
Jackson: I'm not that old, dude. I'm an engineer with six years of professional experience, I think.
Chris: Something like that, right? Yeah. So but you're like, you're like, you have a university degree
Chris: that is very related to this. And you have six years of experience at like,
Chris: like, great companies, right? So it's like, that, that, like, that used to be the gate in order to
Chris: be able to do something like this. And now it's like, any anyone can have a go.
Jackson: That's true. And it was a gate too much of a gate for me to do it.
Chris: Yeah, yeah, me too. Yeah, I've like, I wasn't building a chicken egg app for sure before.
Chris: But like, yeah, a lot of things I wasn't doing that I am now.
Jackson: Yeah, yeah, same here. So now I've got my, my girlfriend researching how to do marketing,
Jackson: we're reaching out to influencers, like the habit chicken distribution, chicken influencer.
Jackson: I'll toss you a hud there. I'll toss you a hud there. Yeah, dude. If you show my chicken
Jackson: app, take a video of you with a chicken egg app, and you're picking up an egg and pressing the plus
Jackson: button. Is there a chick talk like chicken, tick tock, tick tock. There probably is I didn't
Jackson: actually tried to do marketing in my own. And like there's a website called backyard chickens,
Jackson: where you like post pictures of your chickens and talk about chicken problems.
Jackson: There's like, apparently, like, I learned a lot about chickens. And apparently, I like a
Jackson: female chicken get pissed off. And like, they don't want you to touch their eggs.
Jackson: Okay, got a word for that. I can't remember right now, angry female chicken name. I think
Jackson: they call it brooding. Actually, I can't get a brooding. Yeah. Anyways, I tried to post on there.
Jackson: And like, I was reading through the forums and like, so many people have already done that.
Jackson: And they just blocked my face. There's like, Reddit, backyard chickens.
Jackson: They don't want me. So I'm gonna try to go organic. I've been like, calling my dad like,
Jackson: and I'm from Georgia in the United States. I'm like, you know, anybody that has chickens? And
Jackson: he's like, No, and I'm like, everyone thinks Georgia is a farmland. And you have no chickens
Chris: for me, dude. Yeah, you don't even know a chicken. It's crazy. But yeah, I think this is really
Chris: interesting, man. I think like, this is the new paradigm that we're moving into a distribution
Chris: where that really, really matters. And it's like, not a game that I've ever played before. So I'm
Chris: like a little bit nervous. But I'm like, excited to see how it goes. Are you trying at all? Have
Jackson: you tried any distribution of your own trying to sell sigil? I mean, no, I'm trying to distribute
Chris: myself. Like I have a blog, I think I'm going to try to self publish a paper at some point.
Chris: Which is again, like another thing that I just wouldn't have had time to do before. Like the
Chris: setup and like the data harvesting was always like the annoying part. So yeah, I guess like,
Chris: you know, in that sense, I feel like that's a form of distribution. But I haven't like tried
Chris: to distribute a software product yet, or like a proper product. Yeah, I wouldn't I wouldn't even
Jackson: know where to begin. So well, I'll keep you guys updated. If anything happens with the egg app,
Jackson: my girlfriend made her own like seven apps. Amazing. And she's publishing them. And
Jackson: I've got another one that is not AI idea. It's my idea. And wrapping up testing today. So
Jackson: we can't let you have to download it. Yeah, no, we don't tell ideas until there are a lot. No,
Chris: see, I went into the ideas guy time like we're back, we have to like hide our ideas,
Jackson: hide our distribution 100%. Yeah, I don't know if I've ever been idea guy. I don't like work that
Jackson: much. But we're all pivoting. We're all pivoting. Yeah. To close out the segment, if you have
Jackson: chickens or geese, or duck, yeah, and they eat them. Yeah, or you know somebody have them email
Jackson: me at Jackson rocks, number one at Yahoo.com. And I'll send them a link. I'll give them a free
Chris: subscription. They don't have to post a comment on the video, the chicken comment and like and
Jackson: subscribe and hit the bell button also. Oh, yeah, I need to start saying that or wait way earlier,
Jackson: like and subscribe, like and subscribe. No one's liking and leave a comment, say something offensive
Chris: offend us. No, say something nice. Don't do that. No, I read that offensive comments are great for
Jackson: the channel. Oh, okay, then do do that. That's cool. Yeah. Yeah, do do us. And we hope to have
Jackson: Chris or not Chris Tyler back next week. Chris, Chris would never abandon us ever the last time
Chris: you abandoned the pot. Yeah, Tyler's off saving the world. So make sense. That's true. He's he's
Jackson: more important than us. All we have to do is talk on the tour computers. I'm just a humble chicken
Jackson: appreciator. All right, me as well. All right, that closes out the week. Thank you, everybody.
Insert: Peace is up 6% shout out to soul line.